Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Video, 1978-2010; XIX.
  - Attorney General of the United States, 1988-1991; 4.
    - PBS: "MacNeil/Lehrer Report" regarding Crime [online], March 11, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 166)
    - AG News Conference Segments: Exxon Oil Spill Settlement, March 13, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 167)
    - CNN: National Newspaper Association, Speech on Violent Crime, March 15, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 168)
    - NBC Channel 4 "Meet the Press": L.A. Police Brutality Case, Gun Control, and Pan AM 103, March 17, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 169)
    - CNN Newsmaker: AG Interview regarding Crime Bill and Gun Control, April 7, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 170)
    - CNN Crier and Company: AG Crime Victim Impact Testimony, April 18, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 171)
    - C-SPAN I: AG Testimony before Senate Judiciary Committee regarding Comprehensive Crime Control Act (S635), April 18, 1991; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 172 173)
    - AG News Conference following Argument before Supreme Court (Payne vs. Tennessee), April 24, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 174)
    - NBC/ABC/CBS/CNN/MacNeil-Lehrer: Tennessee vs. Payne Supreme Court Decision, April 25, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 175)
    - Department of Justice: Points of Light Ceremony, April 26, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 176)
    - News Conference: Civil Antitrust Case: Eight Ivy League Universities, May 22, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 177)
    - C-SPAN, CNN, CBS "Face the Nation": AG Thornburgh's Resignation, June 7, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 178)
    - PBS: "McNeil-Lehrer Report": Crime Bill and Miranda, June 13, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 179)
    - Fox Morning News: AG Thornburgh's Interview regarding the Crime Bill, June 13, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 180)
    - "Meet the Press" and "This Week with David Brinkley": AG Interviews regarding the Supreme Court Nominee to Replace Justice Marshall, June 30, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 181)
    - First Anniversary of the Signing of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA): DOJ Ceremony [online], July 26, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 182)
    - Various news segments of BCCI story and interviews with the AG, August 4, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 183)
    - AG Press Conference on Drug Strategies, August 7, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 184)
    - President Bush and AG Thornburgh Address at National Fraternal Order of Police in Pittsburgh, PA, August 14, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 185)
    - AG Thornburgh Farewell Ceremony and speech, August 15, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 186)
  - Campaign for Senate, 1991; 5.
    - Senator Harris Wofford Press Conference, State Capitol, Harrisburg, PA, August 6, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 187)
    - WQED-TV; Dick Thornburgh and Sen. Wofford Debate #1, Pittsburgh, PA, September 6, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 188)
    - Dick Thornburgh and Senator Wofford Debate #2, October 18, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 189)
    - Dick Thornburgh for Senate: Compilation of Aired Campaign Ads [online], August, 1991-November 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 190)
    - US Senate Campaign Concession Speech [online], November 5, 1991 (Box 1601, Video DTV 191)
  - Three Mile Island (TMI), 1979-1999; 6.
    - WQED: Press Conference #1, Lieutenant Governor Scranton, Critchlow, Dornsife and Henderson, 10:55AM [online], March 28, 1979; 3 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 204 206)
    - WQED: Press Conference #2, Lieutenant Governor Scranton, Critchlow, Dornsife, Gerusky and Henderson, 4:30PM [online], March 28, 1979; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 207 208)
    - WQED: Metropolitan Edison, Herbein, 1PM [online], March 28, 1979; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 209 210)
    - WQED: Press Conference #3, Lieutenant Governor Scranton, Higgins and Gallina, 10PM [online], March 28, 1979 (Box 1601, Video DTV 211)
    - WQED: Metropolitan Edison, Herbein and Crietz, 10AM [online], March 29, 1979; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 212 213)
    - WQED: 1st Governor Press Conference, Critchlow, Scranton, Gerusky, Higgins, Gallina and Henderson, 5:15 pm [online], March 29, 1979; 3 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 214 216)
    - PBS: "MacNeil Lehrer Report" regarding Three Mile Island (TMI), March 29, 1979 (Box 1601, Video DTV 217)
    - WITF: "Three Mile Island (TMI) Mishap: An Update", March 29, 1979 (Box 1601, Video DTV 218)
    - WQED: Metropolitan Edison, Herbein, 11AM [online], March 30, 1979; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 219 220)
    - WQED: Governor and Lieutenant Governor Press Conference, 12:30PM [online], March 30, 1979; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 221 222)
    - President Carter and Governor Thornburgh Press Conference regarding Three Mile Island (TMI) [online], April 1, 1979 (Box 1601, Video DTV 223)
    - WQED: Harold Denton (NRC) Press Conference, 3 PM [online], April 1, 1979; 2 videotapes. (Box 1601, Video DTV 224 225)
    - WQED: Governor Thornburgh Press Conference 9:30 PM [online], April 3, 1979 (Box 1601, Video DTV 226)
    - Governor's Emergency Message regarding Three Mile Island (TMI), April 6, 1979 (Box 1601, Video DTV 227)
    - WQED: Governor Thornburgh Press Conference, Scranton, Denton and Adamcik, 3PM [online], April 9, 1979 (Box 1602, Video DTV 228)
    - WITF "The People of Three Mile Island (TMI)", 1979 (Box 1602, Video DTV 229)
    - WITF "Newsmakers" with Lieutenant Governor Scranton regarding Three Mile Island (TMI) Consequences, February 28, 1980 (Box 1602, Video DTV 230)
    - News Conference regarding Three Mile Island (TMI): Governor and Harold Denton, March 27, 1980 (Box 1602, Video DTV 231)
    - NBC: "Today Show": Energy and Three Mile Island (TMI) Consequences, March 28, 1980 (Box 1602, Video DTV 232)
    - ABC: Governor regarding Three Mile Island (TMI) Venting, June 29, 1980 (Box 1602, Video DTV 233)
    - NBC: Governor regarding Three Mile Island (TMI) Venting, June 29, 1980 (Box 1602, Video DTV 234)
    - Channel 27 News: David Stockman regarding Federal Dollars for Three Mile Island (TMI) Cleanup, March, 1981 (Box 1602, Video DTV 235)
    - Governor proposes Cost-Sharing Plan for Cleanup of Three Mile Island (TMI) [online], July 9, 1981 (Box 1602, Video DTV 236)
    - National Governors Conference: Governors statement regarding Three Mile Island (TMI), August 10, 1981 (Box 1602, Video DTV 237)
    - Governor's Testimony before joint committees of US Senate regarding cleanup of Three Mile Island (TMI), October 20, 1981 (Box 1602, Video DTV 238)
    - Thornburgh and US Congressman Ertel regarding Three Mile Island (TMI) Cleanup, March, 1982 (Box 1602, Video DTV 239)
    - U.S. DOE and GPU agreement signing for removal of damaged Unit 2 reactor for Three Mile Island (TMI) site, April 7, 1982 (Box 1602, Video DTV 240)
    - PBS: "MacNeil-Lehrer Report" regarding the Three Mile Island (TMI) Cleanup Plan, April, 1982 (Box 1602, Video DTV 241)
    - NRC: Governor's Testimony on Three Mile Island (TMI) before Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), August 8, 1984 (Box 1602, Video DTV 242)
    - "Friendship Under Fire: Remembering Three Mile Island" (TMI) Merrill Lynch produced), March 22, 1989 (Box 1602, Video DTV 243)
    - C-SPAN: National Press Club Speech regarding Three Mile Island (TMI), March 28, 1989 (Box 1602, Video DTV 244)
    - CBS Nightwatch Interview: Three Mile Island (TMI), March 29, 1989 (Box 1602, Video DTV 245)
    - Dickinson College, Clarke Center: "Three Mile Island (TMI) Lessons Learned"; Governor, Denton and others, March 25, 1999 (Box 1602, Video DTV 246)
    - "Three Mile Island (TMI): A Nuclear Crisis Revisited"; University of Pittsburgh Panel Discussion including Governor, Denton, and Dvorchak [online], March 26, 1999 (Box 1602, Video DTV 247)
    - "Thornburgh-Scranton 25th Anniversary Symposium: Crisis Management Lessons from Three Mile Island (TMI)," [online], November 19, 2003 (Box 1602, Video DTV 248)
    - NRC: Three Mile Island Accident, 30th Anniversary: "A Look Back: Preserving the Institutional Memory" (TMI) with excerpts from 'We Survived TMI', WHTM ABC27; Morning Session, [online], March 25, 2009 (Box 1602, Video DTV 249)
    - NRC: "Three Mile Island Accident, 30th Anniversary" (continued); Afternoon Session, [online], March 25, 2009; 2 videotapes (Box 1602, Video DTV 250 251)
  - Ongoing Career, 1993; 7.
    - First Annual Attorneys General Forum, University of California, Hastings School of Law: "American and the Courts", September 14, 1992 (Box 1602, Video DTV 192)
    - Second Annual Attorneys General Forum, University of California, Hastings School of Law, October 23, 1993 (Box 1602, Video DTV 193)
    - Larry King Live regarding the O.J. Simpson Case; Thornburgh guest expert, February 7, 1995 (Box 1602, Video DTV 194)
    - DOJ Official Portrait Presentation of Dick Thornburgh, Washington, DC, September 28, 1995 (Box 1602, Video DTV 195)
    - SIGMA XI Town Meeting "Current Issues in Scientific Research", November 1, 1995 (Box 1602, Video DTV 196)
    - Host Dennis Wholey: "America" regarding Terrorism in America, August 6, 1996 (Box 1602, Video DTV 197)
    - The Eisenhower World Affairs Institute Panel Discussion: "Policy Making in the White House", April 28, 1997 (Box 1602, Video DTV 198)
    - GOP TV: "Rising Tide: Reno's Refusal," Guest Former Attorney General, Dick Thornburgh, October 16, 1997 (Box 1602, Video DTV 199)
    - "Viewpoints": Interview with Dick Thornburgh regarding leadership, his career, and education issues, February, 1998 (Box 1602, Video DTV 200)
    - Speech to SPAS Society, 1998 Lecture Series at the Vineyards: "Challenges, issues and opportunities at the end of 20th century", February 23, 1998 (Box 1602, Video DTV 201)
    - Pennsylvania Cable Network: PIN Profiles: Governor Dick Thornburgh (1979-1987), January, 1999 (Box 1602, Video DTV 202)
    - Vision House: "Opening Doors" (Disability Event and Award), June 3, 2002 (Box 1602, Video DTV 203)
    - Dick Thornburgh: An Oral History Parts 1-3, 3 DVDs (Box 1602, Disc DTV 252)
    - Dick Thornburgh: An Oral History Parts 4 & 5 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 253)
    - Thornburgh-Scranton 25th Reunion, November 19, 2003 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 254)
    - The Jim Bohannon Show, September 23, 2003 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 255)
    - House of Representatives: Commerce, Justice, Science and Related Agencies (CJS) Hearing, Panel 1: Dick Thornburgh, September 14, 2006 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 256)
    - House of Representatives: Commerce, Justice, Science and Related Agencies (CJS) Appropriations Hearing, Panel 2: Dept. of Justice Inspector General, Congressional Research Service, and Director Mueller, September 14, 2006 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 257)
    - Dick Thornburgh Forum for Law and Public Policy, Dick Thornburgh Room, and Judge Jay C. Waldman Seminar Room Dedication, April 5, 2007 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 258)
    - C-SPAN: Puerto Rico's Future, 2007 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 259)
    - C-SPAN: Washington Journal, 2006 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 260)
    - Bill Scranton: Dick Thornburgh Interview, October 16, 2008 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 261)
    - Jim Seif Interview, October 1, 2008 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 262)
    - Rick Stafford: Thornburgh Interview, October 20, 2008 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 263)
    - Thornburgh Delegate: Conversation on Constitutional Convention 1967-1968, ca. 2000 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 264)
    - HBG Living Legacy Interviews, Richard Thornburgh (Box 1602, Disc DTV 265)
    - 9/11: A Memorial & Remembrance, Gov. Dick Thornburgh (Box 1602, Disc DTV 266)
    - Three Mile Island (TMI) Video (Box 1602, Disc DTV 267)
    - I Survived TMI, "27 News Special," 10 Years Out, 1989 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 268)
    - U.S. NRC: Inside Core - Original footage of the damaged core of TMI-2 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 269)
    - Japan Nuclear Accident - Aftermath (Box 1602, Disc DTV 270)
    - Pennsylvania's First Ladies (Box 1602, Disc DTV 271)
    - Enrichment Lecture, February 5, 2004 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 272)
    - Seven Seas Voyager, Enrichment Lectures: Homeland Security and Fight Against Terrorism, February 11, 2004 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 273)
    - Seven Seas Voyager, Enrichment Lectures: Memorable Moments from the 20th Century Presidential Elections, February 12, 2004 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 274)
    - Jeff Brodsky, Columbia University: Dick Thornburgh Interview, October 19, 2010 (Box 1602, Disc DTV 275)